Summary:

A Network Engineer with 6+ years of experience managing a large global multi-vendor enterprise networking infrastructure along with a Master's degree in Computer Networks and Certifications such as CCNP & ITIL Foundations. My area of expertise are Network Engineering & Operations, Network Automation using Python and Linux

Skills:

Platforms – Cisco, Arista, F5, Cumulus, Cloudflare, Akamai, Checkpoint, Palo Alto, Ubuntu, Python, Ansible, Office 365

Tools – ServiceNow, Solarwinds, T-Eyes, Netcool, Splunk, Netscout, Sumologic, Netbrain, Wireshark, Pycharm, GIT

Technologies – TCP, BGP, OSPF, MPLS, IPSEC, QoS, DNS, DHCP, SNMP, VLAN, STP, FHRP, VXLAN, CDN, SR, SDWAN

Certifications - CCNP (R&S: CSCO12739809), ITIL Foundations (GR750402049RD)

Professional Experience:

Staff Network Engineer, Network Reliability Engineering – Visa Inc.

(March 2018-Current)

- Experience with developing Python scripts to automate infrastructure deployment such as device upgrades, auto self-heal of degraded components and collect metrics using API to different monitoring tools
- Collaborate with engineering teams to accomplish design reviews of new network deployments and technologies, do failover testing and document operational runbooks for successful operations handover
- Proven experience partnering with customers to gather requirements and deploying solutions to uplift the existing
 infrastructure, reduce TTD issues by implementing solutions to improve monitoring and telemetry
- Work with level 1 & 2 network teams to analyze requirements or potential problems and proactively develop solutions, enhance tools, develop best practices and continuously refine operational procedure
- Serve as an escalation point for level 2 Network operations team for Priority 1 issues, troubleshoot the issue and constantly work towards improving availability metric by training junior members of the team
- Simulate production environment in the lab set up for DR testing, mock practice of impact scenarios, testing automation solutions and migration plans of new deployments

Network Engineer, Network Operations and Deployment – Visa Inc.

(Nov 2016-March2018)

- Experience implementing and supporting network infrastructure in complex environments comprising of Datacentre, Backbone Core/Edge, CDN, Application Delivery (Load balancing) network
- Expertise in guiding level 1 operations solve issues involving complex deployments with 3-tier security architecture, CDN, VXLAN network fabric using tools such as Solarwinds, T-Eyes, Wireshark, Sumologic
- Collaborate with engineering teams to deploy network migration projects, code upgrade and config push projects using Ansible Tower & Python and creating network diagrams on visio for new deployment

Network Engineer, Network Engineering – Level 3 Communications

(June 2015-Nov 2016)

- Create Python scripts to standardize configuration on M&A devices of the company
- Develop test cases using parsers on Spirent iTest to automate network testing for different vendor platforms

Student Assistant, Computer Network Lab – University of Colorado Boulder

(March 2015-June 2015)

Assemble, Inventory and stage Cisco, Juniper devices, Linux servers to build an advanced computer network lab

Associate Software Engineer – Accenture

(Nov 2013-July 2014)

Deliver client's business requirements using SAP-ABAP programming language

Education:

Masters of Science in Computer Networking, University of Colorado at Boulder

(May 2016)

 Capstone – Designed a resilient Datacenter network with features such as multi-site fault tolerance using VMotion, Load balancing, RSTP, Routing with BFD for fast failover and SSL for encryption